Guide to the Professor William C. Moffit Papers
University of Houston Libraries
Professor William C. Moffit Papers
1930-2008
1960s-1980s
09/2007-025
Moffit, William C., 1925-2008
43.00 linear feet
Special Collections, University of Houston Libraries
The collection includes personal office files, teaching aids, sheet music, and Moffit arrangements of SWC school fight songs. It also contains complete shows for marching band, as well as general formation patterns. There are original Moffit working scores, formations/shows for the Michigan State University Marching Band, the University of Houston Marching Band, and the Purdue University “All-American” Marching Band. It also includes the Patterns of Motion material, ephemera, and awards. Materials range in date from the 1930s to 2008.
Biographical Information:
William C. Moffit was a band director of national importance, whose contributions to musical education gained many honors. He was born in Canton, Ohio on May 13, 1925 and joined the Coast Guard after high school, where he played in the Coast Guard Band. After the end of World War II, he attended Baldwin Wallace College on the GI Bill and attained his degree in 1950. He taught in the public school systems of Ohio and Michigan for ten years before joining the faculty at Michigan State University as a band director, where he taught for nine years. In 1969 he became the Director of the University of Houston Marching Band, where he taught until 1981. Bill Moffit resigned from the University of Houston to take a job at Purdue University, where he taught until his early retirement in 1988. After retiring, he founded the Jacksonville Community Concert Band in Jacksonville, Florida. He is the author of Soundpower, a collection of more than 450 arrangements for marching band and the Patterns of Motion concept in marching. Bill Moffit was the Director of the Fanfare Trumpets at the 1984 Olympics and the Director of the Fanfare Trumpets at the Pan American Games in 1986. The recipient of many honors and awards, he was nominated for the presentation of the Presidential Medal of Freedom and named “Music Arranger Laureate of Indiana” in 1988. His talents as a clinician, a guest conductor, and an adjudicator for music festivals were coveted by many institutions across the country. Bill Moffit died in 2008.
Access Terms
This Collection is indexed under the following controlled access subject terms.
Corporate Name:
Cougar Marching Band (University of Houston); Michigan State University. Band; Purdue University. Band; University of Houston; University of Houston -- Faculty
Genre/Form of Material:
Audiocassettes; Compact discs; Correspondence; Personal papers; Photographs; Plaques (flat objects); Scores; Sheet music; Sound recordings
Personal Name:
Moffit, William C.
Topical Term:
Marching bands; Marching drills
Acquisition Information:
Donated
Accruals:
Additional materials were acquired in 2012 and 2013 as part of a donation by Jeannette Moffit, widow of William C. Moffit. Additional materials were acquired in 2014 as part of a donation from the Moffit family.
Conditions Governing Access:
Open for research.
Scope and Contents
The William C. Moffit collection contains 44 cartons. The collection is organized into 14 series: Personal/Office Files, Teaching Materials, Sheet Music, University Fight Songs, Moffit Arrangements of SWC Fight Songs, Small Sectional Sheet Music, Moffit’s Resource Materials and Michigan State Band Books, Original Working Scores, Formations, Audio Cassettes and Records, Ephemera, Music Books, Awards, and Oversize material.
The collection includes personal office files, teaching aids, sheet music, and Moffit arrangements of SWC school fight songs. It also contains complete shows for marching band, as well as general formation patterns. There are original Moffit working scores, formations/shows for the Michigan State University Marching Band, the University of Houston Marching Band, and the Purdue University “All-American” Marching Band. It also includes the Patterns of Motion material, ephemera, and awards. Materials range in date from the 1930s to 2008.
For preservation and access reasons the collection has been re-boxed and re-foldered. New folder titles conform, as closely as possible, to original folder titles, except when the original was obviously incomplete, incorrect, or confusing. Original folder and item order has been maintained whenever possible. Exceptions were made when folders were obviously misfiled or when no order was apparent.
Detailed List of Contents
- Personal/Office Files
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains 2 boxes of William C. Moffit’s personal and office files. Material includes correspondence, budget information, accounting, meeting agendas, royalties, copyright files, and memos. Also included is biographical material on Moffit, as well as his handwritten letters and notes. This series is arranged alphabetically. Oversized personal/office files can be found in OVS Box 61. Original folder and item order has been maintained whenever possible. Exceptions were made when folders were obviously misfiled or when no order was apparent.
  - Adjudication and Guest Conducting Prior to 1967 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Adjudication and Guest Conducting, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Address Lists (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - American Bandmasters Association, Thirteenth; Friendship Directory, March 2000 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Annual National Band Conductors’ Conference, July 18, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Annual Meeting, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - A Proposal to Compile Business Planning Information (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Application for Promotion to Professor, November 23, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Application for Promotion to Professor, November 23, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Arrangement Requests (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - ASCAP Royalties (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Band Budget Request, 1979-1980 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Bandorama, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Bandmaster’s Association; Sustaining Membership Directory (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Barnet Band; Individual Account; Financial Disclosure (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Berlin Irving; Music Corporation (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Big Three Music Corporation (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Bio Information (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Bob Bradsell Correspondence (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Boiler Brass Music, 1987-1988 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Bregman, Vocco, and Conn (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Business Cards (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Care and Feeding of the Band Musician; Correspondence (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - CBDNA (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Chappell and Co., Inc. (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Christmas Concert; Band and Choir Program (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Clinics, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Clinics, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Clinics, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Clinics, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Clinics, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Clinic Fees and Expenses, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Clinics, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Coat of Arms, undated (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Cole Porter Show (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Commercial Themes Arranged and Published; Bill Moffit (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Copyright Agreements; Blank Forms (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Correspondence, 1960’s (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Correspondence, 1970’s (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Correspondence, 1980’s (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Correspondence, 1990’s, undated (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Cougar Cheerleader Association; 5th Annual Meeting; Ad Brochure (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Cougar Doll; Houston Honey Recommendations (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Cromwell Music, Inc. (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Dena Music, Inc. (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Director’s Schedule (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Embassy Music Corporation (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Equipment Advertisements (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - Expenses, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - Expenses, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - National FFA Convention, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - FFA Band Convention; Notes (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - Famous Music Corporation (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - Feist, Leo, Inc. (Box 1, Folder 54)
  - Film Requests (Box 1, Folder 55)
  - Fischer, Carl, Inc. (Box 1, Folder 56)
  - Football Ticket, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 57)
  - Fourth Annual National Band Conductor’s Conference Workshop, July 21-26, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 58)
  - Frank Music Corporation (Box 1, Folder 59)
  - Golden Crest Records (Box 1, Folder 60)
  - Hal Leonard Music, Inc. (Box 1, Folder 61)
  - Hal Leonard Royalty Agreements (Box 1, Folder 62)
  - Hal Leonard Royalties and Publications Expenses (Box 1, Folder 63)
  - Halftime Planning and Scripts (Box 1, Folder 64)
  - Hallmark Theme (Box 1, Folder 65)
  - Handy Brothers Music Co., Inc. (Box 1, Folder 66)
  - Harrison Hills City School District Form (Box 1, Folder 67)
  - Handwritten Letters and Notes (Box 1, Folder 68)
  - H.C. Berger Company (Box 1, Folder 69)
  - Hefti, Neal, Music (Box 1, Folder 70)
  - Iowa (Box 1, Folder 71)
  - Jax Beach Lyrics; handwritten (Box 1, Folder 72)
  - Jacksonville Beach Song Lyrics (Box 1, Folder 73)
  - Jacksonville Community Band Music Library (Box 1, Folder 74)
  - Job Applications (Box 1, Folder 75)
  - John Richard King; Resume (Box 1, Folder 76)
  - Joy Music, Inc. (Box 1, Folder 77)
  - JU Music; Intercollegiate Band Concert Program, April 16, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 78)
  - Kick-Off Luncheon, January 28, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 79)
  - Lafayette Citizens Band; Summer Concert Series, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 80)
  - Laurel Music Corporation (Box 1, Folder 81)
  - Leeds Music Corporation (Box 1, Folder 82)
  - Letter from Art Indiana; The 500 (Box 1, Folder 83)
  - Letter from the Directors and the Advisory Committee; School of Music (Box 1, Folder 84)
  - Letter from the Prudential Key Realty (Box 1, Folder 85)
  - Letters of Recommendation (Box 1, Folder 86)
  - Letter Regarding Named Professor Chair Nomination at Purdue University, May 2, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 87)
  - Letters of Recommendation; Items of Interest (Box 1, Folder 88)
  - Marching Band Game Procedures (Box 1, Folder 89)
  - Marching Library (Box 1, Folder 90)
  - Marks, Edward B.; Music Corporation (Box 1, Folder 91)
  - Meeting Agenda, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 92)
  - Meeting Agenda, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 93)
  - Memos; Request for Music (Box 1, Folder 94)
  - Memos, undated (Box 1, Folder 95)
  - Memos, 1960’s (Box 1, Folder 96)
  - Memos, 1970’s (Box 1, Folder 97)
  - Memos, 1980’s (Box 1, Folder 98)
  - Memos, 1980’s (Box 1, Folder 99)
  - Michigan (Box 1, Folder 100)
  - Michigan State University; Marching Band Clinics (Box 1, Folder 101)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Miscellaneous Music Publishers (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Miscellaneous Newsletters (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Moffit Article, May 1, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Moffits Marching Library (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Moffit Meeting (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Moffit Meeting; Bill Moffit (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - MPHC Royalty Agreements (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - MPHC Royalties and Publication Expenses (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Music Department (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Music Education Incentives (M.E.I.); Buying Brochures (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Music Manner Inc. (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Music Publishers Holding Corporation (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Music Publishers Holding Corp. (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Music Publishers Who’s Who (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - MSBOA (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - National Adjudicators Invitational Program, May 1, 1999 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - National Freedom Bowl Festival, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - National/International Music Festivals Program, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - N.C.A.A. Report (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Nicsinger Uniform Co., Inr; Order Form, November 16, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Nicsinger Uniform Co., Inr; Order Form, April 5, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Newslife Newspaper, October 23, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - New Mexico (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Notes; handwritten (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Notices to UH Spirit Board, April 7, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Office Equipment and Supplies Purchases (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Ohio State (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Okemos Music Patrons (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Otterhein College; Doctor of Music Degree (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Percussion Pulsations, undated (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Performance Suggestions for Fight Song Arrangement (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Public Relations Letters and Fan Mail (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Purdue University Bands, February 26, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Purdue University Bands; Questions for Rod (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Purdue University Service Work Order (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Radio Stations (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Recommendations to the President for Dr. Moffit; Medal of Freedom (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Recording Tapes and Scores Purchases (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Reference Letters (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Rose Bowl, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Rosemeadow Publishing Corporation (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Royalties, undated (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - Royalties, 1964-1966 (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - Royalties, 1967-1969 (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - Royalties, 1970-1972 (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - Royalties, 1973-1975 (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - Royalties, 1976-1979 (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - Scoring Examples for Contemporary Marching Percussion (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - Senate Enrolled; Act No. 6 (Box 2, Folder 50)
  - Shapiro, Bernstein, and Co., Inc. (Box 2, Folder 51)
  - Shayne, Larry, Music Inc. (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - Simon, George, Inc. (Box 2, Folder 53)
  - Soundpower Titles, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 54)
  - Southern Music Publishing Co., Inc. (Box 2, Folder 55)
  - Spartan Brass (Box 2, Folder 56)
  - Special Arrangement Fees (Box 2, Folder 57)
  - Stationary (Box 2, Folder 58)
  - Stormwork’s; Newsletter (Box 2, Folder 59)
  - Supplies for Band (Box 2, Folder 60)
  - Tabulations/Royalties (Box 2, Folder 61)
  - Tabulations/Royalties (Box 2, Folder 62)
  - Tippecanoe High School; Concert/Symphony Bands; Winter Concert Programs, February 27, 1951 (Box 2, Folder 63)
  - Tree Publishing Company (Box 2, Folder 64)
  - Trinity Christian Academy Band (Box 2, Folder 65)
  - T.V. Broadcast (Box 2, Folder 66)
  - Twirling Resume; Molly Nicholas (Box 2, Folder 67)
  - UH Athletic Department; Travel Expense Summary (Box 2, Folder 68)
  - UH Band Script (Box 2, Folder 69)
  - UH Band Recruiting; Show No. 2 (Box 2, Folder 70)
  - UH Music Advertisement Brochure (Box 2, Folder 71)
  - U.S. Air Force (Box 2, Folder 72)
  - The Modern Band Book II, undated (Ovs box 61, Folder 1)
  - State of Indiana Executive Department; All-American Band Day, 1986 (Ovs box 61, Folder 2)
  - Soundpower Fanfares (Ovs box 61, Folder 3)
- Teaching Materials
  This series contains 3 boxes of a variety of teaching aids and articles referenced by William C. Moffit. Material includes warm-ups for various instruments, articles on various topics of musical education. Also included in this series is a collection of practice drills known as “Finger Busters.” This series is arranged alphabetically. Materials related to “Finger Busters” may also be found in OVS Box 61. Original folder and item order has been maintained whenever possible. Exceptions were made when folders were obviously misfiled or when no order was apparent.
  - Accent; Snare Drums (Box 2, Folder 73)
  - A Teachers ‘If’; no author/date (Box 2, Folder 74)
  - Addenda to Marching with Music, 1951 (Box 2, Folder 75)
  - America; arranged by Bill Moffit (Box 2, Folder 76)
  - MU-230; American Heritage and Popular Music; Test 1 (Box 2, Folder 77)
  - Arranging for the Marching Band; 2 copies (Box 2, Folder 78)
  - Arranging for the Modern Band, undated (Box 2, Folder 79)
  - Arranging Latin-American Music, 1948 (Box 2, Folder 80)
  - Arranging Method for School Bands, 1946 (Box 2, Folder 81)
  - Band Pageantry, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 82)
  - Bandwagon, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 83)
  - Bass Drums Warm-Ups and Exercizes; McIndae, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 84)
  - Black Light Techniques, undated (Box 2, Folder 85)
  - Brass Tone Builders I (Box 2, Folder 86)
  - Building a Show Band (Box 2, Folder 87)
  - Cadenza, March/April 1999 (Box 2, Folder 88)
  - Calisthenics Excerpt (Box 2, Folder 89)
  - 90 Care and Feeding of the Band Musician; Bill Moffit (Box 2, Folder 90)
  - 91 Care and Feeding of the Band Musician; Breathing Calisthenics (Box 2, Folder 91)
  - Care and Feeding of the Band Musician; Middle School Concert Band (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - The Care and Feeding of the Band Musician; Teachers Guide (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Christian Instrumental Director’s Association; Sacred Instrumental Published Music List, Spring 1989 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Colored Light; Band Formations, 1949 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Concert Band Warm-Ups (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Concert Bass Drum (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Concert Sounds, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Corner Drill Movement, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Corps Style Drumming for the Intermediate Drummer; Roger B. Willis (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Corps Style Marching, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Cougar Marching Band; UH vs. UCLA, September 12, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Dare to Dream; William C. Moffit (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Dare to Dream; William C. Moffit (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Differentiated Staffing; Technology in Education; Florida (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - District III; OMEA Band Rehearsal Techniques (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Ed’s Speech Etiquette or Ed’s Vocabulary (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Effective Performance of Band Music, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Electronic Music Educator, September 1988 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Elementary Music Methods; MU 464, Spring 2000 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Expand-O-Scales; middle school (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Fancy Footwork (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Field Drum Warm-Ups (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - The First Thirteen Standard Drum Rudiments (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Finger Busters; C Part (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Finger Busters; Diatonic Patterns; Skip Patterns; Chromatics (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Finger Busters; Field Quads; T-Toms (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Finger Busters; no name (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Finger Busters; manuscript book (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Finger Busters; Soundpower Super Score, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Finger Busters; Middle (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - First Thirteen Drum Rudiments; Second Thirteen Drum Rudiments; Slingerland Drum Co. (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Festival for Percussion, February 18, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Five Hundred and Twenty-Six Ready to Use Modulations, 1935 (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Flexibilies I (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Flexibilies III (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Flexibilies; Middle School (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - Full Chromatic Fingering Chart for Flutophone (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - Fantastic Halftime Productions (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - Function Chorales No. 1-22, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - A Guide to Arranging and Scoring for the Marching or Pep Band, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - The Hal Leonard, undated (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - Halftime as Show Biz (Box 3, Folder 42)
  - Handbook of Marching Tactics, 1956 (Box 3, Folder 43)
  - How to Harmonize Melodies, 1935 (Box 3, Folder 44)
  - How to Stage Bill Moffit’s “That’s Entertaining” Features (Box 3, Folder 45)
  - Houston vs. Utah, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 46)
  - The Influence of Attitudes Upon the Progress of the Instrumental Student (Box 3, Folder 47)
  - Instructions T586A and T586B Thermostats (Box 3, Folder 48)
  - Interlude 1979; Snare Drum (Box 3, Folder 49)
  - Interpretation; Dr. William Revelli (Box 3, Folder 50)
  - Interpretation Techniques in Band Rehearsals (Box 3, Folder 51)
  - Introduction to Music: A Guide to Good Listening, 1958 (Box 3, Folder 52)
  - Irish Blister Coogs; 100-77, undated (Box 3, Folder 53)
  - Jacksonville Community; Band Music (Box 3, Folder 54)
  - The Lafayette Article, 1873 (Box 3, Folder 55)
  - Lesson 1-XV (Box 3, Folder 56)
  - Lifestyle; The World of Twirl, June 10, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 57)
  - Manual of Drill, 1960 (Box 3, Folder 58)
  - The Marching Band (Box 3, Folder 59)
  - The Marching Bands Comparative Techniques in Movement and Music, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 60)
  - Marching Band Percussion Tips; Bill Moffit (Box 3, Folder 61)
  - Marching Band Workshop; Arranging (Box 3, Folder 62)
  - Marching Maneuver Series; Volume 7 (Box 3, Folder 63)
  - Marching Maneuver Series; Volume 10, 1941 (Box 3, Folder 64)
  - Miscellaneous Negatives (Box 3, Folder 65)
  - Michigan State University; the Series (Box 3, Folder 66)
  - Middle Fingerbusters No. 1 (Box 3, Folder 67)
  - Middle School Tone Builders (Box 3, Folder 68)
  - MIDI Music Mathematics Science; 1987 (Box 3, Folder 69)
  - Mindpower, undated (Box 3, Folder 70)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 3, Folder 71)
  - Modern Harmony Part I, 1943 (Box 3, Folder 72)
  - More Than Meets the CBS Eye (Box 3, Folder 73)
  - Music Ed. Program of the Future (Box 3, Folder 74)
  - Music in Your Schools (Box 3, Folder 75)
  - Music Lesson Sheets; Percussion (Box 3, Folder 76)
  - Music to Picture, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 77)
  - Musing with the Moffits Newsletter (Box 3, Folder 78)
  - National/International Music Festivals, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 79)
  - NBA Selective Music for Bands, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 80)
  - New Brass Band Goes for Gold (Box 3, Folder 81)
  - New Sounds for the Marching Band; Bill Moffit; Michigan State University (Box 3, Folder 82)
  - New Sounds for the Marching Band (Box 3, Folder 83)
  - The New Sound in Marching Percussion; Dwayne Sagen (Box 3, Folder 84)
  - News Clippings (Box 3, Folder 85)
  - Obituary; Pamela Trzepacz (Box 3, Folder 86)
  - One Minute Show Calisthenics (Box 3, Folder 87)
  - Percussion for the Marching Band; 5th National band Conductors Workshop, July 1953 (Box 3, Folder 88)
  - Percussion – Performance and Instructional Techniques (Incomplete Photocopy) (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Percussion Pulsations (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Percussion – Scales, Practice Sheets, Warm-Ups (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Pigskin Pageant of 1958 Script (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Purdue University All-American Marching Band – 1985 Music Performance Date (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Playing Counter Melody for the Organ, 1961 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Playing Rock – Basic Rock Beats (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Playing the Recorder (copied pages) (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Practice in Modern Harmony, 1943 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Practical Scoring for the Concert Band, 1961 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Purdue Band Cadences (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Purdue Crowd Well-Behaved (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Purdue Reports Vol. 33, No. 2, October 1982 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Purdue University News – Press Release “Music Make Me Healthy”, April 11, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - “Range Builders” (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Reading Rhythm (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - The Rock ‘N Roll Combo Course, 1967 (5 copies) (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Rubank Intermediate Method – Clarinet (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Rules of Chords, 1936 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Scoring for the Marching Band by Bill Moffit (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - “Shswips” – McIndoe, 1980 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - “Soft Tongue Du-ers” (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Son of the Storm, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Song Names (hand written) Misc. (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Studio Class Manual for Tuba & Euphonium, 1980 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - “Sweat” Arrangements by Bill Moffit in Schirmer’s Manuscript Music Book, 1958 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Teaching Band Instruments to Beginners, 1966 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Teaching Music Through Playing Classroom Instruments (2 pages of this book) (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Tenor Drum (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Titles, 1980 – 1985 (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Training in the School Dance Band, 1956 (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Terry Parker High School – Choral Student Handbook (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - “Tone Builders” (Middle School) (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - Tone Production – Dr. William D. Revelli (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - “Tongue Tippers” (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - “Tongue Twisters” (Legato) (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - U.S. Coast Guard Newsletter #2 USCG Reunion #6, 1992 (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - “Vibrato Studies I” (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - Vibrato Studies I (Box 4, Folder 39)
  - “Warm-Up Drills for the French Horn Student” (Box 4, Folder 40)
  - We’re the 1’s, undated (Box 4, Folder 41)